[Music]
happy New Year sis welcome back to
another video so we are in a New Year
sis and I don't know about you but we
need to get our makeup game up to par
this year we are not slacking we're
learning everything we need to learn
about makeup now I know the Christmas
season and everything just passed so our
bank accounts are really Slim right now
so I make sure to use a very affordable
products to show you guys a step by-step
makeup routine so I showed you guys how
to achieve this very simple everyday
full face of makeup I went step by step
all that good stuff so if you're
interested then I encourage you to
continue watching all right sis so I've
already done my eyebrows so what I did
was used a brow gel so one of my
favorite brow gels and my go-to right
now is my e.l.f brow lift so all I did
was use this brow gel to really flatten
my brows and just stick them in place I
do have a lot of brow hairs to to work
with so that's why I love using a brow
gel it just allows my brows to be really
tamed and in place on top of using the
brow gel I do go in with a brow pencil
so today I did use my Covergirl clean
fresh brow liner I am in the shade black
brown and what I did is just use this to
pencil in any of the areas that were
sparse that didn't have much hair going
on and kind of create a shape for my
brows so that's pretty much what I did
for my brows brows is very unique to
everyone one so whatever you have to do
for your brows I would recommend doing
it first before anything all right so
the first thing is your primer so you
definitely want to have a primer in your
makeup kit now what is a primer a primer
acts as your base so this is the first
and number one thing that you need to
apply on your skin of course after your
skin care this is going to create that
barrier between your skin and the makeup
so you don't want to go directly on your
skin with makeup it's going to be
causing Fine Lines wrinkles it's going
to seep into your skin I always feel
like a primer is just that base at least
in my head it's just going to create
that barrier between my skin and the
makeup so there are different types of
primers if you are oily skin you
definitely want to use a primer that is
mattifying so this is going to make sure
that it controls your oil so that you're
not getting oily throughout the day if
you are dry skin you do want to grab
something that is hydrating this is just
going to allow your skin to be very
plumped very hydrated especially when
you're going to be applying you know
powders on your skin you just want to
make sure that your base is hydrated so
yeah it really depends on your skin type
so make sure that you choose a primer
that is for your skin Ty and then this
is honestly my current favorite this is
the LA girl Pro Prep High Definition
smoothing primer so this is just going
to help with texture if you're someone
who has a lot of Fine Lines large pores
things like that this is just going to
help allow your makeup to look really
smooth on the skin so I am going to be
using this one today and I like to apply
this primer in my T-Zone I I feel like
those areas for me are like my problem
areas these are the areas that I see I
get a lot of makeup issues like Fine
Lines wrinkles oily skin things like
that so I personally like to focus my
primer in my T-Zone but you are open to
use your primer all over your face all
right so now we can move on to our
foundation so what is a foundation a
foundation is going to help conceal and
give you a very even complexion so if
you're someone who suffers with dark
marks acne marks things of that sort
Foundation is just going to give you a
really even canvas so this is why it's
very important to learn your skin type
your skin tone and your skin undertone I
do have a detailed video on how to learn
all of those things so if you haven't
checked that out as of yet I'll leave it
on the screen above so that you can
check it out or you can check it out in
my description box below so for someone
who has dry skin you are really good to
pick up a foundation that is Luminous
luminous or hydrating these are
foundations you want to to pick up if
you are someone who is oily skin you
want to stick to foundations that are
mattifying so it's usually going to
claim mattifying Foundation mattifying
is going to just control your oils if
you are someone who has sensitive skin
you want to choose something that is in
the clean makeup category where it's
more safer for the skin you don't want
to use anything that has too much
ingredients that just don't work well
with your sensitive skin so just making
sure to learn your skin is honestly my
number one tip so an OG Foundation that
I love is the Maybelline Fit Me
foundations now they make it super easy
to choose which foundation will work for
you they do have a matte and poreless
formula and they do have a luminous
hydrating formula so depending on your
skin type you can choose which one works
for you so for me I know I suffer with a
lot of pores and oily skin so I did pick
up the matte and poreless Foundation I
am in the shade 360 so with Foundation I
like to to work in sections I like to
just really be careful with how much
Foundation I'm putting on my skin so I
avoid putting the foundation directly on
my skin from the product I like to start
with putting the foundation on the back
of my hand so whether you have a pump
product or you pour make sure to start
with the back of your hand the back of
your hand will act as your kind of
makeup palette so that you can you know
kind of control how much product you're
putting on your face so with this the
only thing about this is that it isn't a
pump so you definitely want to be
careful with how much you use from this
so I'm just going to pour some on the
back of my hand so I put just about this
much on the back of my hand we're going
to start with a little honestly you
don't need to go in with too much a
little goes a long way but you can
always build up your foundation if you
want so when it comes to the tools on
how you apply your foundation you can
use either a brush or a beauty blender
so I do have both here to show you so
this is my e.l. ultimate blending brush
I really like using this for my
foundations you do want to pick up
something that is dense this is what's
going to help stipple in that Foundation
it's going to give you an even base it's
going to give you a Flawless look so you
definitely want something that is dense
and easy to blend out if you're going to
be using a sponge you definitely want to
make sure that your sponge is damp so
ring it through as much as you can I did
this already so my sponge is ready to go
and this is just going to help blend out
your foundation so I'm going to show you
guys both sides and how I use both tools
so for the brush what I use on the back
of my hand we're just going to dip into
that Foundation kind of warm it on the
back of my hand like this and then we
want to work on the Outer Perimeter of
our skin so I'm just going to start
dabbing this in and what you want to do
is tap it into your skin you don't want
to be swiping this is going to cause
streaks in your foundation so just go in
with stippling motions this is a makeup
term and this is just what's going to
give you a really even Foundation base
and you don't want to forget your neck
your neck does act as part of your face
so make sure that you're always getting
your neck as well so you guys see that I
did work on this section I'm just going
to put a bit of the extra that I had on
my brush on my forehead as well and then
you don't need to worry about putting
any foundation underneath your eyes this
is reserved for your concealer so I try
to use less product underneath my eyes
the less product that you use the less
creasing you're going to deal with so
make sure that you avoid putting any
foundation underneath directly
underneath your eyes all right so this
is one layer of that Foundation I'm
going to show you guys the other side
and as you guys could see I have a
really good match with my Foundation it
honestly does not look like I did too
much to my skin this is what I mean in
terms of finding a foundation that is
your perfect match this is what's going
to set the tone for the rest of your
makeup all right so on this side we're
going to use the sponge so I'm going to
do the same thing and just apply a bit
to the back of my hand and when it comes
to using your sponge I would always
recommend using dots on your face you
don't want to go directly into that
foundation with your sponge a sponge is
going to soak up all that product and we
already know that just on basic science
a sponge does what it does it soaks up
products so you want to make sure that
you're just applying your foundation on
your face in little dots and this is
just going to
also help you control how much you're
putting on your skin so just like that I
applied a few dots and then I'm going to
take the butt end of the beauty sponge
so just the bottom part where it's
usually flat and we're just going to do
the same thing and just dab that
Foundation into the skin now with a
beauty sponge you're not going to get as
much full coverage as you would using a
brush and that is again because you're
using a sponge a sponge is going to be
soaking up a lot of the pigments and the
cover on your skin so if you are going
for a more natural makeup look then of
course using a sponge is like perfect
but if you are going for a more full
coverage look and you want to cover any
dark spots or hyperpigmentation that you
have going in with a brush will give you
a more full coverage look so I'm going
to go in with one more layer for this
side just cuz like I said it's not going
to give the full coverage like I did on
this side so I'm just going to apply one
more layer and then whatever is
remaining on the brush you can go over
your nose your nose is an area where you
don't need to put too much Foundation as
well so try to use as Little Foundation
as you can for your nose all right so
just like that we have our base so this
is what we mean as your base so it's
giving you a very even natural
complexion so making sure that you
choose a foundation that is your exact
skin tone is like what's crucial for
this step all right so now we're ready
to move on to the concealer so what is a
concealer so concealer is going to
conceal it's going to cover any dark
spots that you have in little areas so
concealer is really good for concealing
underneath your eyes so if you're
someone who has a lot of dark circles or
even bags underneath your eyes a
concealer is going to help conceal those
and just allow them to be very smooth
and one even skin tone also if you do
suffer with little acne marks or scars
on your skin using concealer helps to to
conceal those as well so you can
definitely use a concealer before your
foundation to do a bit of spot
correcting or you can use it after
honestly it's it doesn't matter you can
use them either or it is also used to
highlight so when it comes to doing a
full face like I'm showing you guys
today a concealer that is two to three
Shades lighter than your complexion is
going to help brighten and just bring
back the natural highlights to your skin
so today I am going to be using the
concealer to brighten and highlight my
face so I'm going to show you guys an
example I do have the L'Oreal true match
serum concealers and I do have them in
two shades so this is what I mean by two
to three Shades lighter so this one
would be my perfect match this is what
I'd use if I want more of just a natural
concealer something to just give me an
even base underneath my eyes or just to
spot correct I'd use something that is
my perfect match and then I would go
about two to three Shades lighter to get
my highlighting Shades so this one is in
the shade n10 and this one's in the
shade N8 so that's about two shades
lighter so this is what I mean by two to
three Shades lighter so when it comes to
highlighting your face you want to make
sure that you're highlighting the areas
that the light hits so these are common
areas everyone should be highlighting
these specific areas so it would be your
forehead underneath your eyes your
Cupid's bow and your chin technically
your T-Zone so you want to make sure
that you're highlighting those areas a
light is going to reflect the areas that
you want to highlight so I do have my
ring light in front of me and this is
showing me the areas on my skin that the
light hits so again right here you could
see the little bit of lighting right
here on my forehead all underneath my
eyes my Cupid's bow and my chin so I'm
going to go in with this concealer today
now when it comes to concealers for
beginners I always recommend working in
sections this is just going to help you
use less product really take your time
with blending if you need the extra time
with blending it's just easier to work
in sections for your beginners so I'm
going to work in sections today and
we're going to work on the under eyes
first so I'm going to apply this to the
inner corner now when it comes to the
tools for your concealer you can either
go in with your sponge so with your
sponge you'd want to use the tip this is
just going to help you blend out that
concealer a little better or you can go
in with a concealer brush so I do have
my e.l.f Flawless concealer brush today
and this is pretty much just a mini
Foundation it's small but it's dense so
you always want to make sure that you're
using something that's dense this is
just going to help blend out your
concealer so today I'm actually going to
use the brush actually I'll show you
both I'll show you both sides and how to
use them so on this side we'll use the
brush and what you want to do is just
start stippling in stippling is going to
be the word of today just because that
is how you're going to blend out your
concealer so you always want to start
with blending out the edges first of
that concealer and then work your way in
the inner corner and you do want to
apply some on the sides of your nose
this is is just going to help with your
nose Contour later on but all you want
to do is just stipple that concealer
into your skin very simple very easy you
guys saw that in real time so with your
beauty sponge you want to kind of pinch
the tip this is just going to allow you
to really get underneath your eyes and
blend out that concealer so again we're
going to start by blending out the edges
and then work our way in now this
specific concealer I use today is a
serum concealer so it's a lot more
thinner it's not full coverage and I
think I want a bit more coverage
underneath my eyes so I'm just going to
put one more layer of this concealer
this is definitely optional you do not
need to do this step but I'm going to
apply just a little bit under my eyes
and I'm going to take my brush and just
blend it out
again all right so once you've done your
under eyes you can now move on to the
other areas so that's my forehead here
and you can see literally where my ring
light is hitting so it's right here
where you want to apply that concealer
down the bridge of your nose your
Cupid's bow and your chin I'm just going
to put a little bit right in the center
above my brows down my nose my Cupid's
bow and my chin I'm just going to use my
brush to blend the rest out when it
comes to your nose Contour you just want
to make sure that you're keeping that
concealer just straight in the middle
you don't want it to go here or here you
want it straight in the middle this is
is going to this everything we're doing
here is going to help with your nose
contour and when it comes to your
forehead concealer you want to just make
sure you're keeping that concealer right
in the middle here it does not need to
go anywhere further on your forehead all
right so just like that we brought back
the natural highlights to our skin
before we move on to the next step you
want to make sure that you're blending
out all the harsh lines making sure that
everything honestly looks seamless and
blends well together so you either go
back in with your sponge the butt end
where you use the foundation or your
brush and just go over all the edges of
that concealer and your foundation this
is just going to make sure that
everything Blends there's no harsh lines
you really want your skin to still look
like skin all right so now we can move
on to our Contour so what is a contour a
contour is going to bring back the
Shadows to your skin so like I said once
you put on Foundation you are getting
rid of your highlights you're getting
rid of your natural Contours to your
skin so Contour is going to bring all of
that back so when we talk about Contour
we're talking about the perimeter or the
outer portion of our face so these are
essentially the areas that the light
doesn't hit so your forehead your
cheekbones your jawline and also the
sides of your nose these are considered
areas that you want to Contour so when
it comes to a full face of makeup we're
reconstructing our face so really think
of it that way like you're bringing back
the Contours and all that stuff to your
skin so I do have two products here two
drugstore products I have the Covergirl
True Blend skin enhancer Contour balm
and this one is more of a newer product
I actually haven't used it so I think I
want to use it in today's video and then
I also do have the Nyx wond stick this
is one of my favorite Contour sticks
this is in the shade deep and when it
comes to Contour you want to make sure
that you're grabbing a shade that is two
to three Shades Darker so just like our
highlighting concealer you want to make
sure that your Contour is two to three
Shades Darker than your Foundation shade
so this is what's going to give you the
Contours and just bring back the natural
Contours to your skin so like I said I'm
going to use the Covergirl Contour balm
and the areas that you want to Contour
is your cheekbones your forehead your
jawline and the size of your nose when
it comes to your cheekbones you do not
need to put a lot of product you don't
need to be drawing a whole line all the
way to your mouth that is just not what
you need to do so I always recommend
finding the tip of your ears like the
top of your ears and just creating a l a
Short Line going down so just like this
so just create a small line just like
that and then for your forehead you just
want to apply maybe about three lines on
your forehead and then your jawline as
well and then taking the same foundation
brush you can definitely reuse your
foundation brush for your Contour or you
can go in with the butt end of your
beauty sponge as well either or works
you do want to start just dabbing that
in and this is just going to bring back
some Shadows to your skin now this
Contour stick is is a bit lighter than I
thought but it does give me a really
subtle Contour which is good especially
if you're going for a natural look and
when it comes to blending out your
jawline you want to make sure that you
just keep the product right where your
jawline is you don't need to make it go
down or up onto your skin and then when
it comes to your forehead you just want
to blend it outwards towards your temple
or into your hairline so you guys
essentially see what the Contour did it
just brought back some Shadows to my my
skin and kind of gave me some Dimension
and then for your nose you just want to
create a small line going down the Sid
so this is going to complete your nose
contour and then the tool that I like to
use is my angled brush so I get asked a
lot of times where I got this this I got
from quo so it is a Canadian brand but I
do believe there is a dupe or not a dupe
another version of this in the morphe
which I'll leave in the comment section
below for you guys to check out all it
is is an angled brush this is just going
to help me blend out my nose contour and
you just want to keep it right on the
sides as you can see I just completed my
nose Contour all right so before I move
on to the powders to just set all of
this in place I'm going to move back on
to my concealer and just shape up my
brows and conceal my eyelid so you guys
can see that my eyelids are pretty dark
right now and my brows can use some
shaping up so I'm going to take my
L'Oreal concealer and a flat brush so
anything that's flat this is just going
to help you shape your brows so that it
gives you a more sharper look and what I
do is just apply some to the brush and
then start tracing out the brows and
then taking the concealer brush that I
used earlier we're just going to blend
this out and all I'm doing is blending
it towards my eyelids cuz we're going to
be concealing that as well I'm just
going to put a bit of that concealer on
the lids and blend that
out all right guys so just like that
we've applied all of our cream products
so now we're ready to move on to some
setting powder all right so what is a
setting powder used for so a setting
powder is going to set all of your
highlighted areas so these are the areas
that we use that concealer this is just
going to make sure that your makeup does
not budge and that everything is set
when you do go in with liquids or cream
products it is essential to set your
makeup with a setting powder so when it
comes to setting powders a really good
setting powder is anything translucent
so depending on your skin type
translucent deep is something I would
recommend for anyone from medium dark or
deep skin tones would really love a
translucent medium deep setting powder
so I have two drugstore makeup products
that I like to Interchange between so
that's either the Black Radiance true
complexion loose setting powder this is
in the shade honeymoon and this is
essentially a medium deep setting powder
or there is the Covergirl clean
invisible loose setting powder and this
is in the shade it translucent deep so I
am going to go in with my Black Radiance
if you have been watching my videos you
know this is a go-to I like to go in
with a velour puff so this is the wander
Beauty velour puff this is what I'm
going to be using just to apply that
powder and just set everything in place
you can also go in with your damp Beauty
sponge so if you are going to be using
this go in with the pointed area as well
and this is just going to allow you to
set that as well you can get these on
Amazon for like 10 bucks a pack of six
or eight I believe I'm not sure the
amount but very affordable you can also
wash them and reuse them so definitely
something to invest in for your makeup
kit so I'm going to dip into that powder
and what I'm going to do is take the
excess of that powder off on the back of
my hand this is just going to help me
not apply too much powder to my face I
can always go back in and add more if I
want and then before going in with that
powder I'm just going to take my
concealer brush and blend out my
concealer make sure that I'm not setting
any creases the last thing you want to
do is go in with your powder on top of
creases make sure that you're blending
that out before going in with that
powder and then what you want to do is
just press that powder into your skin
just like that just follow the areas
that you applied your concealer and as
you could see that gave me a really
subtle under eye look we set it you can
physically see the difference between
both eyes so that is essentially what a
setting powder is going to do so I'm
just going to do the same thing for the
rest of the areas that we use the
highlighting concealer you also want to
put some on your eyelids and underneath
your brows my forehead as well down the
bridge of my nose all right sois so just
like that you physically see that we've
powdered the skin so you definitely want
to make sure that you're including this
step when you're going in with a full
face of makeup this is just going to
ensure that the creams and the liquids
that you've applied on your face is
going to stay put so next we're going to
go in with some bronzer so what is a
bronzer a bronzer is going to bring back
some warmth to your skin so the
difference between contour and bronzer
is Contour is going to Chisel you out so
it's going to bring back the Shadows
chisel you out give you a more sharper
look whereas a bronzer is going to just
warm back your skin so give you some
natural warmth to the skin everyone has
warmth to their skin so that's
essentially what your bronzer is going
to do so today I'm going to be us using
the Nyx butter melt bronzer this is in
the shade butter than you and then for
my bronzer I like to go in with an
angled brush like this one here this one
you can also use for your Contour but
this is just going to allow you to apply
that bronzer in all of the areas that
you Contour you can also go in with a
more fluffier brush like this as well
something like this is just going to
lightly brush on that bronzer honestly
it's up to you I think I do want to go
in with this today so we're going to dip
into this bronzer and my I warn you this
bronzer is super pigmented so I always
recommend going in with a little bit as
you can see that really just did a lot
just now so definitely be careful with
this bronzer but all you want to do is
just brush along all the areas that you
applied your Contour this is just going
to bring back some warmth to the skin
and then going back in with my small
angled brush we're just going to dip
into that and just go over the nose
Contour as well so essentially every
where that we've applied any kind of
cream or or liquid product we just want
to go back over it with some powder
taking my velour puff you guys can see
that my nose Contour is way too harsh
just going over that line that you just
created really helps to just tone down
how harsh your nose Contour is just like
that all right so I know a lot of us are
into blushes now especially cream
blushes I didn't include any Cream Blush
in today's video just cuz I wanted to
keep this very basic and beginner
friendly I wanted to just create a very
natural easy makeup look for beginners
so I'm going to show you guys powder
blush powder blush is just very easy to
apply so today I am going to be using my
Sephora collection colorful blush this
is in the shade overthe toop and when it
comes to blush you definitely want to
choose a shade that is going to
complement your skin tone for darker
skin tones I usually aim for more plums
Reds anything of the deeper
tones so those I feel work really good
for deeper complexions so I'm going to
use this blush today and for my brush
I'm going to go in with my Marabella
blush Contour brush and you want to use
something that is more tapered the brush
is essentially supposed to hug the
apples of your cheeks so anything that's
pointed or just hugs The Contours of
your cheeks is the type of brush you
want to use for your blush so I'm going
to go ahead and dip into this dust off
the excess and we're just going to apply
some to to the apples of the cheeks and
what I did is just kind of applied it to
literally where that cheekbone is and
just stippled it into my skin so I
applied it right above the bronzer and
the Contour and this is just going to
bring back some color make you look
alive all right guys so now we can move
to the more intricate parts of our face
so that's our eyes and our lips so
speaking of eyes what I like to do for
the eyes just to keep it very simple and
beginner friendly is just go back into
to my bronzer and taking just a regular
eyes Shadow brush something like this
we're just going to dip into that
bronzer and just apply some to our
eyelids this is just going to bring the
eye look together and make it look like
we did a little something to the eyes so
going back in to my NYX bronzer I'm
going to dip into that with my eyeshadow
brush and we're just going to apply that
bronzer to the crease of our eyes and
this is just going to give me a very
simple eyeshadow look we're not doing
the most with our eyes so all we're
doing is just applying that bronzer into
the crease all right so just like that
we just added a bit of that bronzer to
the eyelids now we could go in with a
kajel pencil so I always recommend just
a normal kajal pencil I do have my
Essence kajel pencil eyeliner in the
shade black so we're going to use this
today to apply to the top lash line and
the bottom lash line and when it comes
to a kajel pencil I just like to create
really short Strokes to just Trace out
the top lash line and just a trick for
your lash line using your pinky and
resting it on your face really helps to
control the control that you have for
the eye pencil so if you want to just
really control how you're applying your
eyeliner don't do it like this place
your pinky on your face and this is just
going to give you the control all right
and then also you want to just apply in
your waterline so once you have your
eyeliner on on you can now choose
between applying eyelashes or your
mascara so whichever one you want to
choose you can definitely do as you guys
know I do like applying my lashes so I
am going to be using my Ardell Demi
wispies I just like how lashes really
completes to look for me so I'm going to
quickly pop these on I do have a
detailed eyelash tutorial so if you're
interested in how to apply lashes you
can definitely check that out I'll leave
it on the cards
above all right so just just like that
we've applied the lashes and you guys
could see how that just brought the eye
look together essentially using your
mascara will do the same thing so I am
going to use my mascara this is the
Maybelline Sky High mascara and I'm just
going to apply this to my bottom lashes
this is just going to complete the eye
look all right so now we can move on to
the lips so with the lips it's very
versatile you can do exactly what you
want to do whether it be a lip gloss a
lipstick lip oil whatever the case is it
is up to you the look that I did is
pretty basic it's very natural so you
can use just about any type of lip
products to complete your makeup look
for me I love a nice Brown lip liner and
nude lipstick so that's what we're going
to do today I am going to take my padio
eyeliner pencil so you guys have seen
this it's an eyeliner pencil but I use
it as a lip liner and I'm going to use
my Black Radiance perfect tone lip gloss
so I'm going to take my lip liner and
just line my lips
so I'm just going to go in with my Black
Radiance perfect tone lip gloss this is
just a really nice nude
gloss and just like that we have
completed the look so last thing guys is
your setting spray now a lot of people
ask me why do I use a setting spray what
is a setting spray used for so a setting
spray is going to set and lock your
makeup in place so so if you know you're
going to be wearing your makeup for a
long period of time you definitely want
to use a setting spray this is just
going to make sure that your makeup
lasts throughout the day nothing budges
everything stays put so today I am going
to be using the Milani make it last
original natural finish setting
spray all right and that completes the
makeup look guys so today was a very
detailed makeup look at that so video
was lengthy but that's okay because we
went through everything that you would
need to complete just a basic look like
this so this is considered a natural
full face of makeup um we use all
drugstore products so very affordable
products so I hope you guys enjoyed
today's video I do have a similar video
to this one that you can check out I'll
leave it on the screen right here and
this is just another very easy beginner
makeup tutorial that you can follow
along and really learn how to do your
makeup so if you are free and still have
some time check out this video and that
is about it for today's video I will see
you guys in my next one bye guys